- 发现什么情况了吗？上尉 - 没有，长官
- Anything, lieutenant? - No, sir.
我已经试过戴内瓦星上所有主要的传输站了
I've tried every major transmitting station on Deneva.
没有一个回应我的通话请求
None of them have acknowledged my contact signal.
试试GSK-783，子空间频率3
Try GSK-783, subspace frequency three.
但是，长官，那是一个私人传输站的信号
But, sir, that's a call sign for a private transmitter.
我很清楚，上尉，试试吧
I'm very well aware of that, lieutenant. Try it.
好的，长官
Yes, sir.
史波克，说说你的看法
Evaluation, Mr. Spock.
舰长，据我推测
As I speculated, captain,
这样大规模摧毁文明的疯狂行径
the overall pattern of mass insanity destroying civilizations
大致发生在这部分星系的一条直线上
follows an almost straight line through this section of the galaxy.
这里，有着古老文明的波托兰贝塔星系
Over here, the Beta Portolan system, the ancient civilizations.
考古学家们给我们的信息指出
Archaeologists have given us information indicating
他们是这次暴行的开端
that they were the beginning.
两百年前，拉维尼娅5号星被劫掠一空
Two hundred years ago, Lavinius V was swept by mass insanity.
然后是天鹅座西塔12号星
Then Theta Cygni XII.
最近一次是发生在两年前的英格拉姆B星
The last was Ingraham B, two years ago.
这条路线的下一站，是戴内瓦星
And next in line, Deneva.
老骨头，你觉得这是由什么引起的？
Bones, what's your theory about the cause of all this?
不能用医学或科学来解释发生在那些星球上的事
There is no medical or scientific cause for what happened on those planets.
但是这种行为有很明显的趋势
But it follows a definite pattern,
从一颗行星…
a systematic progression from planet...
- …到另一颗行星的星系推进 - 舰长
- ...to planet. - Captain.
在监视器里发现一艘飞船
We're picking up a ship on our sensors
正朝着戴内瓦太阳星飞去，飞船会烧毁的
heading directly into the Denevan sun. He'll burn up.
苏鲁先生，用曲速8前进，准备拦截
Plot an interception course, Mr. Sulu. Warp factor 8.
马乎拉上尉，快联络那艘飞船
Lieutenant Uhura, try to contact that ship.
是的，长官
Aye, aye, sir.
舰长，那是艘戴内瓦外形的单人飞船
The ship is a one-man vessel of Denevan configuration, captain.
看起来不像是飞船失控，他的航向直指向太阳
He does not seem to be out of control. His course is straight for the sun.
史考特，用牵引波束
Scotty, tractor beams.
长官，超出传输范围
Out of range, sir.
舰长，我们取得联络了
Making contact, captain.
戴内瓦号，这里是联邦星舰进取号
Denevan ship, this is the USS Enterprise.
你是否可以调转你的航向？
Can you reverse your course?
请回复
Acknowledge.
舰长，我们离太阳越来越近了
Captain, we'll get too close to the sun.
继续前进
Keep closing.
戴内瓦号，调转你的航向
Denevan ship, reverse your course.
你能听到吗？
Do you hear me?
调转你的航向
Reverse your course.
请回复
Acknowledge.
星舰外壳温度已达到480度，并且在持续上升
Outer hull temperature, now 480 degrees and rising.
- 舰长，他靠太近了 - 我们也是
- He's too close, captain. - So are we.
外壳温度达到1000度，并且在持续上升
Hull temperature, 1,000 degrees and rising.
太阳的重力牵引在不断增加
Sun's gravimetric pull increasing.
我做到了
I did it.
它终于死了！我自由了
It's finally gone! I'm free.
我——
I'm--
舰长，飞船着火了
He burned up, captain.
调转航向，180度左右
Reverse course, 180 degrees about.
是的，长官
Aye, sir.
舰长，一切正常，星舰外壳温度正在下降
All clear, captain. Hull temperature falling.
重力牵引下降到可接受水平
Gravimetric pull approaching tolerance level.
好的
Very well.
将速度降低到亚曲速
Reduce to sub-warp speed.
我们去戴内瓦星
Take us to Deneva.
是的，长官
Aye, aye, sir.
那艘戴内瓦飞船是故意飞向太阳的
That Denevan ship headed deliberately into the sun.
- 为什么？ - 有一种可能性
- Why? - There's one possibility.
大规模疯狂灾难也许已经蔓延到这颗星球了
The mass insanity may have reached this planet too.
舰长，我现在不能向戴内瓦星发送信息
Captain, I'm having difficulty on that transmitter call to Deneva.
- 继续联络 - 是的，长官
- Keep trying. - Yes, sir.
吉姆，你哥哥山姆，他们一家
Jim, your brother, Sam, his family,
不是定居在这颗星球上吗？
aren't they stationed on this planet?
宇宙，最后的边疆
Space, the final frontier.
这是星舰进取号的航程
These are the voyages of the starship Enterprise.
它的五年任务，是去探索未知的新世界
Its five-year mission: to explore strange new worlds,
找寻新的生命与新的文明
to seek out new life and new civilizations,
勇敢的航向前人未至之境
to boldly go where no man has gone before.
【星际迷航：原初】
-=THE LAST FANTASY=-
荣誉出品
本字幕仅供学习交流，严禁用于商业途径
-=TLF字幕组=-
翻译：sholto
校对：诸星龟龟
第一季第二十九集
歼灭行动
舰长日志，星历3287.2
Captain's log, stardate 3287.2.
我们追踪到的那场横扫星系这块区域的大规模暴行
The mass insanity we have tracked across this section
似乎已经蔓延到戴内瓦星了
of the galaxy seems to have already touched Deneva.
那颗星球，在一百多年前被开辟成殖民地
That planet, colonised over a century ago,
是这个星系最美丽的星球之一
is one of the most beautiful in the galaxy.
舰长，这个星球的发展历程很正常
Planet development is normal, captain.
起初作为这片区域的运输线基地被开辟为殖民地
Originally colonised as a freighting line base in this area.
是的，他们定期从这里出发
Aye, they make regular trips from here,
为小行星带的矿工们运输物资
carrying supplies to the asteroid belt for the miners
并把货物运出来
and bringing cargo out.
作为工程顾问
I've made the run a couple of times myself
我自己做过好几次运输
as an engineering advisor.
超过一年没有和联邦联络
No Federation contacts for over a year.
舰长
Captain.
长官，我已经和你的私人传输站取得了联系
I've made contact with your private transmitter, sir.
接到扩音器上
Put it on audio.
请快点来，救救我们
Please hurry. Help us.
我没有时间了，他们会知道的，求你了！求——
I don't have much time. They'll know. Please! Please--
奥瑞兰，我是吉姆，在进取号上
Aurelan. This is Jim on the Enterprise.
重复你说的话
Repeat your message.
- 长官，通话断了 - 再联络
- Contact broken, sir. - Re-establish.
- 抱歉，长官 - 我对你的道歉不感兴趣
- I'm sorry, sir. - I'm not interested in your excuses.
再联络那个传输站
Re-establish contact with that transmitter.
舰长，恐怕现在不可能
I'm afraid that's impossible at the moment, captain.
他们立即停止广播了
They stopped broadcasting immediately.
他们没有回应我的联络信号
They do not acknowledge my contact signal.
- 继续试着联络他们 - 是的，长官
- Keep trying to raise them. - Yes, sir.
吉姆
Jim.
- 你认识那个女人吗？ - 是的
- Did you know who that woman was? - Yes.
你刚才说中了
You were right a while back.
我哥哥山姆住在戴内瓦星
My brother, Sam, lives on Deneva.
他是一个研究生物学家
He's a research biologist.
那个女人…
That woman...
听起来像是他的妻子奥瑞兰
It sounded like his wife, Aurelan.
你们的相位枪设为击昏模式，我们将直接传送到首都
Set your phasers on stun. We'll beam directly into the capital city.
保持警戒状态
Alert status.
史波克先生？
Mr. Spock?
乌乎拉上尉对信号的追踪没什么进展
Lieutenant Uhura has had no further response to our signals.
感应装置报告在星球表面发现了很多人类
Sensors report the expected number of humans on the planet surface.
但是，他们表现地异常平静，极少有活动
However, they are strangely quiet, very little activity.
我想要了解到底在那座星球上发生了什么
I'll want a complete transcript of everything that happens down there.
- 遵命，长官 - 我们出发吧
- Yes, sir. - Let's go.
开始传送
Energize.
戴内瓦星上大约有一百万居民
There are almost a million inhabitants of Deneva.
单单这座城市里就有10万多人
There's more than 100,000 in this city alone.
人都到哪里去了？
Where is everyone?
舰长，他们在建筑物里
They're here, captain. In the buildings.
这里安静地让人害怕
Strangely quiescent.
我哥哥的实验室就在那边
My brother's lab is over there.
他们曾给我们发送过信号
They signalled us once.
那里一定有人
There should be someone there.
让我们去看看发生了什么
Let's find out what's happening.
舰长，有几个人向我们接近了
Captain, several people approaching.
退后，赶快走，退后！我们不想伤害你们！
Go back! Run, get away! We don't want to hurt you!
- 退后！ - 离开！
- Go back! - Beat it!
- 退后！ - 快离开这里！
- Go back! - Get out of here, please!
快跑，离开这里！
Run! Get away!
- 走开，快离开这里！ - 快离开这里！
- Go away! Get out of here now! - Get away!
- 快跑，离开这里！ - 我们不想伤害你们！
- Run! Get away! - We don't want to hurt you!
准备开火
Stand by to fire.
开火！
Fire!
- 你听到他们说的话吗？ - 听到了，他们好像
- Did you hear what they said? - Indeed. They seemed concerned
- 担心我们的安全 - 但他们想用这些棒子
- for our safety. - They tried to brain us
把我们的脑壳敲开，老骨头，检查下他们
with these clubs. Check them out, Bones.
他们的思维和行动不一致
Their attitude was inconsistent with their actions.
至少说明一点
To say the least.
吉姆，这里出状况了
There's something wrong, Jim.
他们的神经系统…
Their nervous systems...
非常不清醒，他们应该是身不由己地行动
Unconscious like this, there should be just routine autonomic activity.
但是我能看出来
But I'm getting a very high reading,
即使在他们不清醒的内心里
as though, even in their unconscious state,
他们也深受刺激影响
they're being violently stimulated.
散开，跟着我
Fan out. Follow me.
警戒
Security.
他们来了，他们来了！
They're here! They're here!
求你了，不要让他们过来！
Please, keep them away!
- 他们来了！ - 奥瑞兰，我是吉姆
- They're here! - Aurelan, it's Jim.
- 他们来了！ - 奥瑞兰，我是吉姆，老骨头
- They're here! - It's Jim, Aurelan. Bones.
奥瑞兰
Aurelan,
你现在安全了
you're safe now.
吉姆，这是你哥哥吗？
Is this your brother, Jim?
山姆
Sam.
他确实是我哥哥
It is my brother.
曾经的哥哥
Was my brother.
我很抱歉，吉姆
I'm sorry, Jim.
这个男孩神志不清，但还活着
The boy's unconscious, but he's still alive.
皮特
Peter.
吉姆，我最好还是把这个男孩和他母亲带回飞船上
I'd better get the boy and the mother back to the ship, Jim.
我在这里不能给他们治疗
I can't do much for them down here.
好吧，准备传送到星舰
Get ready to beam up.
麦考伊呼叫进取号
McCoy to Enterprise.
准备传送四个人到星舰
Prepare to beam up party of four.
舰长，我理解你——
Captain, I understand how you--
是的，谢谢你，麦考伊先生
Yes. Yes, Mr. Spock.
你也听见了我嫂子说的话
You heard my sister-in-law say something
她说“他们”在这里，你怎么看？
about "they" being here. Your guess.
舰长，注意通风设备
Notice the ventilator, captain.
他们很明显是想要阻止什么东西进来
Apparently, they were trying to keep something outside from getting in.
但显然，他们没有成功
Obviously, they were not entirely successful.
这讲不通，报告没有说这里有有害生物
That doesn't make sense. There are no harmful life forms reported.
我们的传感系统未收集到不属于这里的生物信息
Our sensors didn't pick up anything that didn't belong here.
你说的对，我也很不理解
That is correct. I am at a loss to understand it.
舰长，我们准备好传送了
Ready to beam up, captain.
我希望你嫂子恢复意识时，你也能在船上
I'd like you to be onboard when your sister-in-law regains consciousness.
史波克先生，你来掌管登陆部队
Take charge of the landing party, Mr. Spock.
你一定要找到一切的起因
I want some answers to all this.
在我没有把实验室的金属板放回位置之前
I won't be able to give you the exact cause
我不能给你确切的答复
until I get the plates back from the lab.
他们都很痛苦，我给他们注射了镇定剂
They're both in extreme pain. I've sedated them heavily.
但是你嫂子的身体像是有很强的抗性
But your sister-in-law seems to have a high tolerance.
镇定剂对她没起多少作用
The tranquilizer hasn't affected her much.
她能说话吗？
Can she talk?
是的
Yes.
奥瑞兰
Aurelan.
奥瑞兰，我是吉姆
Aurelan, it's Jim.
吉姆？
Jim?
山姆，他…
Sam. He's...
他死了
He's dead.
但是你的儿子还活着
But your son's still alive.
你得帮助我们
You've got to help us.
你来了
You are here.
吉姆，真的是你
It is you, Jim.
是的，我在这里
Yes, I'm here.
奥瑞兰，你得告诉我们发生了什么事
You have to tell us what happened, Aurelan,
你和其他人都遭遇了什么
to you and the others.
他们来了…
They came...
…在八个月前
...eight months ago.
谁来了？
Who?
难以言说的东西
Things.
恐怖的东西！
Horrible things!
游客用飞船把他们从一颗行星带过来
Visitors brought them in their vessel from a planet,
英格拉姆B星
Ingraham B.
什么样的东西？
What kind of things?
那并不是船员们的错
Not the ship's crew's fault.
那些东西控制着他们来到这里
The things made them bring their ship here.
奥瑞兰
Aurelan,
告诉我是什么样的东西
it's important that you tell us
这对我们很重要
what kind of things.
那不是他们的错
Not their fault.
当她回答问题时
When she answers questions,
任何问题
any questions,
好像要挣扎着才能说出答案
it's as if she's fighting to get the answers out.
就好像有东西为了阻止她说话而不断制造疼痛感
As though something is exerting pain to stop her.
他们就是用疼痛来控制我们的
They use it to control us.
吉姆，他们还在扩散
They're spreading, Jim.
他们利用我们做宿体
They need us to be their arms and legs.
他们强迫我们为他们建造飞船
They're forcing us to build ships for them.
不要让他们…
Don't let them...!
不要让他们继续肆虐下去了！
Don't let them go any further!
我兄长的儿子…
My brother's son...
吉姆，我会竭尽所能救他的
I'll do everything I can, Jim, to save him.
- 报告情况 - 道路异常安静
- Report. - The streets are extraordinarily quiet.
我们没见到其它戴内瓦星人
We've seen no other Denevans.
那些我们先前击晕的人在我们出来时就不见了
And the ones we stunned earlier were gone when we came out.
你看到过其它生物吗
You've seen some kind of creature,
长得像外星人？
any alien form?
没有，长官，这里只有我们听到的噪声
None, sir. There's just that noise we heard.
一种特殊的嗡嗡响声
A peculiar buzzing sound.
我们刚要去检查下
We were about to investigate it.
好吧
All right.
让我们去看看那是什么东西
Let's go find out what it is.
把你们的相位枪调到可以杀伤的3级功率
Set your phasers on force 3, to kill.
我们要去寻找某种生物
We're looking for some kind of creature.
我们已经了解到它很危险，能致人死亡
And we already know it will kill.
史波克！
Spock!
围成一个圆圈
Form a ring.
开火！
Fire!
真不可思议
Incredible.
它不但没有被相位枪摧毁
Not only should it have been destroyed by our phasers,
而且我的三录仪都没有它的相关记录
it does not even register on my tricorder.
舰长，它甚至看起来都不像是真的
Captain, it doesn't even look real.
根据我们的认知，它没有生命
It is not life as we know or understand it.
然而很明显，它活着，它存在着
Yet it is obviously alive, it exists.
它能够抵抗相位枪最大功率射击
And it can bear up under full phaser power.
舰长，我建议冒险把它带到船上
Captain, I suggest we risk taking it aboard.
这里太靠近它了，这或许是个圈套，我们快走
It's too closed in here. It may be a trap. Let's move out.
史波克
Spock.
史波克！
Spock!
没事了，你能站起来吗？
It's gone. Can you stand?
史波克，你还好吗？
Spock, are you all right?
舰长日志，补充部分
Captain's log, supplemental.
不管那种生物是什么
Whatever the creatures are,
很显然他们控制住了戴内瓦星上所有的居民
they have apparently taken over all the inhabitants of Deneva.
同时，舰队医疗官麦考伊
Meanwhile, ship surgeon Dr. McCoy
正在检查那只生物在史波克先生背上留下的
is examining a strange puncture wound
奇怪刺穿伤
left by one of the creatures on Mr. Spock's back.
护士
Nurse.
这已经是第二次试图从他的身体里取出那东西了
That's the second time he's come out of it.
如果不是他抗拒我们…
Either he's fighting us...
…就是他身体里的东西在抗拒我们
...or something inside of him is fighting us.
医生，即使在史波克先生身上
Doctor, the readings have never looked like that before,
这样的数据也非比寻常
not even on Mr. Spock.
准备缝合伤口
Let's prepare to close.
护士
Nurse.
医生，我们不应该就这样结束
Doctor, that's not all you're going to do?
- 查佩尔小姐 - 医生，还有更多的东西在他身体里
- Miss Chapel. - Doctor, there is more of it in him,
盘根错节，遍布身体每个部位
entwined all through his body.
查佩尔小姐，如果你不能像我要求的那样协助我
Miss Chapel, if you cannot assist me as required,
那就叫其他护士过来
call another nurse in here.
要么协助我，要么叫其他人来
But do one or the other now.
他怎么样了？
How is he?
实话说，吉姆，我不清楚
To be very frank, Jim, I don't know that I can do anything
我能为史波克或你的侄子做些什么
for Spock or your nephew.
这是那种生物的组织切片
Pieces of some form of living tissue.
我从史波克的脊髓中取出一部分
I removed one from Spock's spinal cord,
其余的都是从你嫂子身体里取的，都是一样的
the other from your sister-in-law's body. They're both the same.
你侄子太虚弱了不能动手术
The boy's far too weak to touch.
而且，据我所知，移除这些组织
Besides, the removal of the tissue
并不能免除疼痛
wouldn't stop the pain anyhow, as far as I can tell.
你及时为史波克做手术了吗？
Did you operate on Spock in time?
不，不，我只是移除了部分组织来检测
No, no, no. I just removed these for examination.
他的身体里都是这样的触须
His body's full of these tentacles,
缠绕并在他的神经系统滋长
entwining and growing all about his nervous system.
我的侄子呢？
My nephew?
他的情况也是那样
The same.
很明显的，当那种生物攻击时
Evidently, when the creature attacks,
会留下一根刺，就像蜜蜂或黄蜂那样
it leaves a stinger, much like a bee or a wasp,
在受伤者身体里留下身体的一部分
leaving one of these in the victim's body.
然后它会迅速掌控受伤者的身体
And it takes over the victim very rapidly.
而且与身体结合得非常非常紧密
And the entwining is far, far too involved
以至于常规的外科手术不能移除
for conventional surgery to remove.
有什么建议吗？
Recommendations?
吉姆，抱歉
I'm sorry, Jim.
实验室，科学部…
The lab, the science departments...
…我们都束手无策
...we're all stumped.
不
No.
史波克先生
Mr. Spock.
不，我不会屈服
No, I won't.
史波克先生——
Mr. Spock--
舰桥，这里是医务室
Bridge, this is Sickbay.
请告诉麦考伊医生，史波克先生刚离开了
Tell Dr. McCoy Mr. Spock just left here.
他有些发狂，可能会对人造成危害
He's delirious, possibly dangerous.
所有船员，安全戒备状态
All decks, security alert.
找到并制止史波克先生，他可能很危险
Locate and restrain Mr. Spock. He may be dangerous.
如果需要的话，用相位枪将他击昏
Use phasers, on stun, if necessary.
- 一定要控制飞船 - 史波克——
- Must take ship. - Spock--
我必须…
I must...
…驾驶飞船降落！
...take it down!
把他送回医务室
Get him back to the Sickbay.
用束缚带绑牢他
Use security restraints.
K-3指示器记录了疼痛的程度
The K-3 indicator registers the level of pain.
当我打开它时，注意观察
Now, watch it as I turn it on.
看，这就是他所经历的疼痛
Now, that's what he's been going through.
我从没见过这样的事，难怪这个可怜的家伙会发狂
I've never seen anything like it. No wonder the poor devils go mad.
麦考伊先生
Dr. McCoy.
舰长
Captain.
史波克
Spock.
我不需要束缚带了
These restraints will no longer be necessary.
医生，我也不需要镇定剂了
Nor will your sedatives, doctor.
我能回归自己的岗位了
I'll be able to return to duty.
我为先前的被软弱控制
I apologise for my weakness earlier,
试图控制飞船而道歉
when I tried to take control of the ship.
我只是不理解
I simply did not understand.
史波克先生，你有什么不理解的？
What is there to understand, Mr. Spock?
医生，我是个瓦肯人
I am a Vulcan, doctor.
疼痛是心理的感受
Pain is a thing of the mind.
而心理是可以被控制的
The mind can be controlled.
你只是半个瓦肯人，你还是会受到影响
You're only half Vulcan. What about the human half of you?
它给我造成了不便
It is proving to be an inconvenience,
但还是可以解决的
but it is manageable.
那个生物，用它数以千计的触须
The creature, with all of its thousands of parts,
甚至是现在，还在压迫我
even now is pressuring me.
它想要这艘星舰，但我在顽强抵抗
It wants this ship. But I am resisting.
老骨头，他真的能控制住自己吗？
Can he control it the way he says, Bones?
吉姆，我不知道
Who knows, Jim?
我了解那个生物在他身上产生的疼痛感
I know the amount of pain the creature can inflict upon him.
但是史波克是否能一直控制住自己…
But whether he can control it, hour to hour...
舰长，我有自己的意愿
I have my own will, captain.
- 让我来帮你吧 - 史波克，我很需要你
- Let me help. - I need you, Spock.
但是我们不能冒险
But we can't take any chances.
我们需要再观察你一段时间
We'll keep you confined for a while longer.
如果你能够…
If you can...
…持续地控制自己的情绪…
...maintain control...
…我们会看到的
...we'll see.
我的侄子
My nephew.
如果他恢复了意识，他是否也会经历那样的痛苦？
If he regains consciousness, will he go through that?
是的
Yes.
帮帮他们
Help them.
不管付出什么代价
I don't care what it takes or costs,
你都得帮帮他们
you've got to help them.
吉姆，你难道忘记了？
Jim, aren't you forgetting something?
这下面的星球上有超过100万居民
There are over a million colonists on that planet down there.
拯救他们同样是你的责任
Just as much your responsibility.
他们也需要你的帮助
They need your help too.
我是一个瓦肯人
I am a Vulcan.
我不会感觉到疼痛
There is no pain.
史波克先生
Mr. Spock.
我还以为你还待在医务室观察呢
I thought you were still confined to Sickbay.
我康复了
I was.
站住，你要到哪里去？
Here, now. Where do you think you're going?
我要去星球表面一趟
I have an errand on the planet surface.
你把我传送到先前的同一坐标点
You will beam me down to the same coordinates as before.
不可能，史波克先生
Not likely, Mr. Spock.
史考特先生，这是命令
That is an order, Mr. Scott.
是的，长官
Aye, sir.
但抱歉，我不得不违背它
And I'm sorry I have to disobey it.
舰长命令说不准任何人传送下去
The captain said no one was to transport down.
史波克先生
Mr. Spock.
站在那里别动，史波克先生…
Freeze right there, Mr. Spock...
…不然我就开枪了
...or I'll put you to sleep for sure.
我是传送室的史考特
This is Mr. Scott in the Transporter Room.
帮我接通舰长
Get me the captain.
史波克先生，我曾命令你待在医务室里
Mr. Spock, I gave you an order to stay in the Sickbay.
直到疼痛消失，舰长
Until the pain was gone, captain.
我已经重新掌控了身体的主导权
It has been discontinued, by me.
史考特？
Scotty?
长官，他说他要到星球表面上去
He said he was transporting down to the surface, sir.
而你下命令，除非有你的授权，否则没人能传送下去
Your orders were that no one was to beam down unless you authorised it.
我感觉史波克先生已经下定决心了
And knowing Mr. Spock's determination on some things,
所以我想最好还是在询问过你之前，把他留在这里
I thought I'd better hold him here until I got your orders.
舰长，一定要抓住一只那种生物
One of the creatures will have to be captured
我们才能对它进行分析
and analyzed, captain.
在我被袭击之前
We did not have a clear opportunity to do so earlier
我们没有这样的机会
when I was attacked.
既然我的神经系统已经被感染了
Since my nervous system is already affected,
就像你指出的那样，医生
as you pointed out, doctor,
我不觉得它们能对我再造成什么伤害了
I don't believe they could do much more to me.
吉姆，这很荒谬
Jim, this is ridiculous.
我不想我的病人到处乱跑，他应该躺在床上
I don't want my patients running around. He should be in bed.
医生，我能完全掌控自己的意识
I am in complete control of myself, doctor.
我既然能站在这里，就说明我不需要再待在床上了
The fact that I am here proves that I do not belong in bed.
史波克先生
Mr. Spock.
你的逻辑，一如往常…
Your logic, as usual...
…让人不能辩驳
...is inescapable.
把他传送下去，要和我们保持紧密联系
Beam him down. Stay in constant touch with us.
把你的相位枪给他，他会需要的
Give him your phaser. He'll need that too.
谢谢你，舰长
Thank you, captain.
开始传送
Energize.
吉姆，史波克很虚弱
Jim, that man is sick.
别跟我讲该死的逻辑
And don't give me any damnable logic
说他是最适合做这件事的人
about him being the only man for the job.
老骨头，我不必说，我们心里都明白
I don't have to, Bones. We both know he is.
进来吧，先生们
Come in, gentlemen.
我相信你们会觉得这个东西很有趣的
I believe you'll find this interesting.
医生，你的医术和好奇心
Doctor, your medical skill and curiosity
都让我很钦佩，但是我向你保证，我很好
are quite admirable, but I assure you, I'm all right.
史波克先生，你或许能控制疼痛
You may be controlling the pain, Mr. Spock,
但你离康复还差得远呢
but you're far from all right.
医生，这件事现在不重要
Unimportant at the moment, doctor.
请注意观察
Please observe.
有趣吧，先生们
Interesting, gentlemen.
一个单细胞生物，竟然比其他任何事物
A one-cell creature resembling, more than anything else,
都更像一个巨型的个体脑细胞
a huge individual brain cell.
嗯，这就已经能说明很多问题了，是不是？
Yes, that would answer a lot of questions, wouldn't it?
舰长，你明白我的意思了吗？
Do you understand what I'm suggesting, captain?
我想是的
I think so.
这或许是一个体积更大生物的一个细胞
This may be one cell in a larger organism,
实际上，应该是一个巨大无比的生物
an incredibly huge organism, in fact.
而且，尽管它并没有和其他细胞结合在一起
And although it is not physically connected to the other cells,
但可以肯定，它一定是那整个生物的一部分
it is, nevertheless, part of the whole creature.
由整体指挥
Guided by the whole, drawing its strength
从整体中获得力量
from the whole, which probably accounts
这或许能解释它对我们相位枪的异常抵抗力
for its unusual resistance to our phaser weapons.
它们如此特别
Existing so differently
和我们所知的任何生命或能量形式都不同
from any living matter or energy
它们或许来自一个完全不同的星系
as we know it that it may have come here,
经过一颗颗星球，来到这里
planet by planet, from an entirely different galaxy.
在那个地方，我们的物理定律不能适用
From a place where our physical laws do not apply.
舰长，我们还发现很难毁灭它
We may therefore find it difficult to destroy, captain.
但不是不可能，史波克先生
But not impossible, Mr. Spock.
那个飞向太阳的戴内瓦星人最后哭喊着说他自由了
The Denevan that flew into the sun cried out that he was free,
他获胜了
that he had won.
先生们，这是一个很好的研究方向
That's the angle to work on, gentlemen.
我需要医学和生命科学部门在一小时内
I want an analysis of all this
对这一切进行分析
from Medical and Life Science departments within the hour.
是，长官
Yes, sir.
舰长，我很抱歉，我已经试了所有的方法
I'm sorry, captain. I've tried everything I can.
不同的辐射，甚至高达9000度的高温
Varying radiation, intense heat, even as great as 9,000 degrees.
你在浪费时间
Then you're wasting your time.
一定有一种方法
It has to be something that will kill the creature
既能杀死那种生物又不会伤害到人类宿主
without destroying the human host.
这也是我想要说的，这种生物杀不死
Which happens to be my point: The thing won't die.
即使用能把史波克和你外甥
Even at temperatures and radiation
烧成灰烬的高温和射线
which would burn Spock and your nephew to ashes.
老骨头，我不能接受你的说法
I can't accept that, Bones.
这艘星舰上有14个科学实验室
We've got 14 science labs aboard this ship.
还有这个星系最好的设备和计算机
The finest equipment and computers in the galaxy.
舰长
Captain.
我理解你的忧虑
I understand your concern.
你对史波克的爱戴
Your affection for Spock,
还有你侄子是你哥哥一家唯一的幸存者
the fact that your nephew is the last survivor of your brother's family.
不，不，老骨头
No. No, Bones.
现在不止两个人的性命堪忧
There's more than two lives at stake here.
我不能让它扩散到殖民地外面去
I cannot let it spread beyond this colony,
即使这意味着…
even if it means destroying...
…要牺牲星球上的一百万人
...a million people down there.
舰长日志，星历3289.8
Captain's log, stardate 3289.8.
我正面临着人生最艰难的选择
I am faced with the most difficult decision of my life.
除非我们能找到方法
Unless we find a way to destroy the creatures
既能消灭那些生物，又不会伤害到人类宿主
without killing their human hosts,
否则我作为指挥官的职责就会迫使我
my command responsibilities will force me to kill
牺牲上百万人
over a million people.
先生们？
Gentlemen?
舰长，很遗憾你没有其他的选择了
I regret I see no other choice for you, captain.
据我们所知，这种生物已经摧毁了三种文明
We already know this thing has destroyed three civilizations,
- 或许更多 - 先生们，我也想消灭它们
- perhaps more. - Gentlemen, I want it stopped too,
但是不是用100多万人的生命做代价
but not at the cost of destroying over a million people.
包括我自己，医生
Including myself, doctor,
还有寇克舰长的侄子
and Captain Kirk's young nephew.
我能理解你的感受
Understandably upsetting.
但是一旦它从这里扩散出去
But once it spreads past here,
它将控制几十个殖民地
there are dozens of colonies beyond,
感染数十亿人
and billions of people.
如果杀5个人能救10个人，我们就该去做
If killing five people saves ten, it's a bargain.
史波克先生，这就是你的简单逻辑吗？
Is that your simple logic, Mr. Spock?
先生们，两者我都不会选
I will accept neither of those alternatives, gentlemen.
我不会让这种生物从这颗星球上扩散出去
I cannot let this thing expand beyond this planet,
我也不会为了阻止它杀害100万或更多的人
nor do I intend to kill a million or more people to stop it.
我要另一种办法
I want another answer.
我要你们俩也和我一起思考
I'm putting you gentlemen on the hot seat with me.
我想要第三种方法！
I want that third alternative!
- 给我报告 - 吉姆，抱歉
- Report. - I'm sorry, Jim.
我们已经一遍遍看过报告了，任何可能性都测试过了
We've been over it and over it, we've made every conceivable test.
因此我才请求批准将我传送到星球表面上去
I therefore request permission to beam down to the planet's surface.
我还建议你的侄子跟我一起
I also suggest your nephew accompany me.
我不批准你的请求
Request denied.
舰长
Captain.
我并不是轻率得做出请求
I do not make this request lightly.
我不知道自己还能抵抗这种疼痛多长时间
I do not know how much longer I can hold out against the pain,
但是我知道如果那个男孩恢复意识
but I do know what the boy will go through
他也会经历这种疼痛
should he regain consciousness.
我不批准
Request denied.
一定还有其他的解决方法
There must be another answer.
在那个戴内瓦星人死之前
Something in the sun killed that thing,
太阳里的东西就已经杀死了那种生物
before the Denevan died.
是的
All right.
你已经试过了高温
You've tried heat,
射线
radiation.
太阳还有什么其他的特性或属性？
What other qualities or properties does the sun have?
它是真实存在的
It exists physically.
它占据空间
It occupies space.
它是物质构成的，因此有重力
It has mass, therefore gravity.
它将物质转化为能量
It converts matter to energy.
吉姆，我们一遍又一遍地研究过了
Jim, we've been through it and through it.
辐射，高温…
Radiation, heat...
但还有一种东西你们没有提到
But one other thing you haven't mentioned.
那就是光
It's bright.
如果你靠得足够近的话，它会发出强光
It radiates a blinding light, if you're close enough.
光不会致命
Nothing lethal about light.
不是对我们，而是对星球地面上的生物
Not to us. But down on the surface,
那种生物，大部分都待在阴暗处
the creatures stayed in the shadows, for the most part.
假设他们并不是简单地为了躲避
Suppose that they weren't simply hiding.
假设他们对某些光很敏感
Suppose they're sensitive to light.
比如说离太阳足够近时的太阳光
Light, like in a sun, close up.
有可能
A possibility.
吉姆，你不能把戴内瓦星搬到接近太阳的地方
You can't move Deneva closer to the sun, Jim.
是的，但我们可以把等同于太阳光的东西送到戴内瓦星上
No, but you can move the equivalent of the sun to Deneva.
- 史波克先生？ - 是的
- Mr. Spock? - Yes.
这个我们可以实现
In essence, it can be done.
一圈围绕着行星的卫星
A string of satellites around the planet,
携带燃烧着的三菱镁矿和三锕
with burning trimagnesite and trevium.
嗯，我可以在生物实验室弄一个试验间
Well, I can rig a test cubicle in the bio lab,
把我们的样本放到里面
put our specimen in it,
- 但我不… - 好的
- but I don't-- - Good.
让我们开始吧
Let's get on it.
你确信你的计算是正确的吧？
Your figures are, of course, accurate?
当然
Of course.
那个戴内瓦星人说他解放了的地方
The light of the sun at the proximity
其附近太阳的亮度相当于
where the Denevan declared himself free
在每平方英寸点燃100万根蜡烛
was 1 million candles per square inch.
如果这办法行的通
If this works,
我们发射的卫星
the satellites we orbit will produce light
将产生亮度非常高的光芒
of such intensity that even someone
甚至在封闭、阴暗地方的人也会受到影响
in a closed, darkened area will be affected by it.
医生，准备好了
Ready, doctor.
带上眼罩
Put on your masks.
试验结束了
Completed.
起作用了，我们找到对付他们的方法了
It worked! We can do it.
吉姆，你怎么了？我们找到对付他们的方法了
What's the matter, Jim? We can do it.
目前只是在实验室起作用
It worked in a lab,
那个生物没有任何遮挡或保护
with the creature exposed to everything we can give it.
但是这会对被感染的人产生什么影响？
But what about the people who are infected?
我不知道，这或许只是试验性质的，并且——
I don't know. It may be trial and--
现在没时间做假设了，老骨头
Maybe. There's no time for maybes, Bones.
我们现在就要知道
We need to know now.
但是我不得不——
But I'd have to put--
是的，我们不得不把一个被感染的人放到光照下
Yes, we'd have to put someone who's infected under that light.
你知道这样做有多大的风险吗？
Do you have any idea of the risk?
我们必须复制那个星球上的环境…
We have to duplicate the conditions on the planet...
…而且，史波克…
...and Spock...
舰长
Captain.
你的下一步试验需要一个宿主
You'll need a host for the next step in the test,
好判定那种生物是否会被驱逐出身体
to determine whether the creature can be driven from the body.
我是最适合的人
I am the logical choice.
你知道每平方英寸100万根蜡烛点燃的光
Do you know what 1-million-candle light per square inch can do
会对你的视觉系统产生什么样的影响吗？
to your optic nerves?
老骨头，没有其他的办法了
There's no other way, Bones.
我们必须复制
We have to duplicate the brilliance that existed
那个戴内瓦星人说他解脱时的光强度
at the moment the Denevan declared himself free.
好吧，我给你弄一副防护性的眼罩
All right. I'll rig up a protective pair of goggles.
医生，星球表面上是不会有那种东西的
There will be none on the planet's surface, doctor.
我也赞同不带眼罩
I agree completely.
不幸的是，你们是对的
Unfortunately, you're both right.
这是我们唯一可做的了
It's the only thing we can do.
好吧，史波克先生
All right, Mr. Spock.
史波克先生是星舰上最好的大副
Mr. Spock's the best first officer in the fleet.
执行吧
Proceed.
试验结束了
Completed.
史波克，你还好吗？
Spock, are you all right?
我身体里的那个生物已经消失了
The creature within me is gone.
我摆脱了它，也摆脱了疼痛
I am free of it and the pain.
并且我也…
And I am also...
…失明了
...quite blind.
医生，这是笔公平的交易
An equitable trade, doctor.
谢谢你
Thank you.
医生，对那个生物的首次试验结果依然…
Doctor, the results of the first test on the creature's remains...
哦，不
Oh, no.
怎么了？
What is it?
我用全光谱照射那个生物
I threw the total spectrum of light at the creature.
其实并不需要那样做
It wasn't necessary.
我居然没有停下来思考
I didn't stop to think that
是不是只要一种光就能杀死那种生物
only one kind of light might have killed it.
有趣
Interesting.
就像是狗会对人类听不到的
Just as dogs are sensitive to certain sounds
某些声音特别敏感
which humans cannot hear,
这种生物很明显也对我们看不到的
these creatures evidently are sensitive to light
光亮特别敏感
which we cannot see.
你是在说…
Are you telling me...
…史波克先生本不必失明的？
...that Spock need not have been blinded?
吉姆，我完全可以把致盲的白光屏蔽掉
I didn't need to throw the blinding white light at all, Jim.
- 史波克，我—— - 医生
- Spock, l-- - Doctor,
这也是我的选择
it was my selection as well.
事情已经过去了
It is done.
老骨头…
Bones...
好好照顾他
Take care of him.
舰长，正在完成发射轨道
Completing the seeding orbit, captain.
210颗紫外线卫星已经就位
Two hundred and ten ultraviolet satellites now in position,
高度72英里
72 miles altitude,
位于行星永久轨道
permanent orbit about the planet.
好的，扫频仪呢？
Good. Scanners?
- 长官，扫频仪准备好了 - 非常好
- Scanners ready, sir. - Very well.
- 准备好了吗，荷尔姆？ - 准备好了，舰长
- Ready, helm? - Ready, captain.
卫星控制中心，我是舰长
Satellite control, this is the captain.
启动所有卫星
Energize all satellites.
收到
Affirmative.
舰长，所有卫星都已启动
All satellites operative, captain.
舰长，收到地面站发来的消息
Captain, receiving messages from a ground station.
汇报情况
Report.
长官，那些生物变得奄奄一息了，这方法起作用了
The things are dying, sir. It's working.
医务室
Sickbay.
我是麦考伊
McCoy here.
告诉史波克…
Tell Spock...
…方法起作用了
...it worked.
是的，舰长
Yes, captain.
他听到这条消息会很高兴的
He'll be happy to hear that.
老骨头…
Bones...
…这不是你的错
...it wasn't your fault.
老骨头
Bones.
文书，向星舰司令部汇报
Yeoman, record this for Starfleet Command.
- 长官，准备好了 - 戴内瓦星上的外星生物
- Ready, sir. - The alien creatures on Deneva
- 已全部被消灭—— - 舰长，看，史波克先生
- have been destroyed-- - Captain, look. Mr. Spock.
史波克
Spock.
你能看见了
You can see.
吉姆，失明是暂时的
The blindness was temporary, Jim.
他的视觉神经
There's something about his optical nerves
和人类的并不一样
which aren't the same as a human's.
舰长，这是一种遗传性状
An hereditary trait, captain.
瓦肯太阳的亮度
The brightness of the Vulcan sun has caused the development
使得他们长出了一个内眼睑
of an inner eyelid, which acts as a shield
在遭遇强光照射时会起到遮挡的作用
against high-intensity light.
医生，这完全是本能反应
Totally instinctive, doctor.
我们会忽略它，就像你会忽略自己的阑尾
We tend to ignore it, as you ignore your own appendix.
史波克先生
Mr. Spock.
重获光明对多数人来说应该是一次情绪体验
Regaining eyesight would be an emotional experience for most.
你真的没什么感受吗？
You, I presume, felt nothing?
正好相反，舰长，我有很强烈的反应
Quite the contrary, captain. I had a very strong reaction.
我第一眼见到的就是麦考伊医生弯腰俯视我的脸
My first sight was the face of Dr. McCoy bending over me.
史波克，很遗憾这段短暂失明的经历
It is a pity brief blindness did not increase your appreciation
- 并没有增加你对美好事物的感激欣赏 - 如果你们说完话了
- for beauty, Mr. Spock. - If you gentlemen are finished,
史波克先生，你是否介意设定去第十星球基地的路线？
would you mind laying in a course for Starbase 10, Mr. Spock?
舰长，这是我的荣幸
My pleasure, captain.
与众不同的眼睛构造
Unusual eye arrangement.
我就知道他会那样的
I might've known he'd turn up with something like that.
- 怎么了，医生？ - 我说，不要告诉史波克
- What's that, doctor? - I said, please don't tell Spock
我说过他是星舰上最好的大副
that I said he was the best first officer in the fleet.
为什么不呢，谢谢你，麦考伊医生
Why, thank you, Dr. McCoy.
医生，你太关注他那瓦肯人的眼睛了
You've been so concerned about his Vulcan eyes, doctor,
你忘记了他还有敏锐的瓦肯耳朵
you forgot about his Vulcan ears.
- 苏鲁先生，用曲速率1前进 - 好的，曲速率1前进
- Ahead warp factor 1, Mr. Sulu. - Warp factor 1, sir.
TLF字幕组欢迎你，欢迎有志之士加入
TLF中文字幕站http://tlfsubs.eastgame.org/